<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Programming Language</string>
    <string name="judul">Bahasa Pemograman</string>
    <string name="desc">description</string>
    <string name="bahasa_pemrograman">Bahasa Pemrograman</string>
    <string name="about">about</string>
    <string name="ahmad_mufli_ramadhan">Ahmad Mufli Ramadhan</string>
    <string name="laxmiwatimaani_gmail_com">Laxmiwatimaani@gmail.com</string>
    <string name="share">Share</string>

    <string-array name="data_name">
        <item>C</item>
        <item>Haskell</item>
        <item>JavaScript</item>
        <item>Kotlin</item>
        <item>C#</item>
        <item>Golang</item>
        <item>Java</item>
        <item>Php</item>
        <item>Python</item>
        <item>Scala</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="data_description">
        <item>C is a procedural programming language developed by Dennis Ritchie in the early 1970s and is known as the intermediate-level programming language. It is widely used for the development of system software, such as operating systems, compilers, and various applications that require high performance.  operating systems, compilers, and various applications that require high performance. C is also the foundation for many programming languages such as C++, Java, and C#.

        </item>

        <item>Haskell is a purely functional programming language that first appeared in 1990. It was designed to model computational mathematics and offers strong support for data types and high-level function handling. Haskell is often used in academic research and in applications that benefit from a functional approach, such as statistical analysis and machine learning. Its focus on immutability, lazy evaluation, and robust type systems makes Haskell ideal for tasks where mathematical precision and safety are paramount. Additionally, Haskel expressive syntax and powerful abstractions enable developers to write concise, efficient, and highly maintainable code for complex problems.
        </item>
        <item>
            JavaScript is a dynamic, high-level programming language primarily used to create interactive elements on web pages. Initially, JavaScript was limited to client-side development, mainly for manipulating the DOM (Document Object Model) to enhance user interfaces. However, with the introduction of Node.js, JavaScript has expanded to server-side development, enabling it to run on the server and making it a versatile language for both front-end and back-end development. Its ability to work across different environments has solidified its position as one of the most popular languages for web development.

        </item>
        <item>
            Kotlin is a modern programming language developed by JetBrains, designed to work seamlessly with Java and run on the JVM (Java Virtual Machine). Kotlin has gained increasing popularity, especially in Android app development, due to its simpler syntax and the introduction of new features that are not available in Java. It also provides excellent interoperability with Java, allowing developers to use both languages within the same project. Furthermore, Kotlin offers enhanced safety features, such as null safety, which helps reduce common programming errors, and supports functional programming paradigms, giving developers more flexibility and conciseness in their code. Additionally, Kotlin can be compiled to JavaScript or native code, making it a versatile choice for cross-platform development.
        </item>

        <item>
          C# is an object-oriented programming language developed by Microsoft for application development on the .NET platform. It is widely used for developing desktop applications, games (especially with the Unity game engine), and web applications built on the .NET framework. C# offers a rich set of features, such as strong typing, garbage collection, and support for modern programming paradigms like asynchronous programming and LINQ (Language Integrated Query). Additionally, its deep integration with the .NET ecosystem makes it a powerful tool for building scalable, high-performance applications across various domains.

        </item>

        <item>
            Go, or Golang, is a programming language developed by Google in 2009. Go is designed to provide efficiency and simplicity in the development of large-scale applications, with strong support for concurrency and extremely fast compilation. Its simplicity makes it easy to learn and maintain, while its concurrency model, using goroutines, allows developers to efficiently handle multiple tasks simultaneously. Go is particularly popular for building distributed systems, cloud services, and microservices due to its performance and scalability. Additionally, Go features a robust standard library and built-in tools that facilitate testing, profiling, and debugging.
        </item>
        <item>
            Java is an object-oriented programming language widely used for enterprise application development, Android apps, and server-side applications. Java is well-known for its (write once, run anywhere) principle, meaning that Java code can run on multiple platforms without requiring modification, thanks to the Java Virtual Machine (JVM). Its platform independence, along with strong memory management, security features, and extensive libraries, makes Java a popular choice for large-scale applications. Java robust ecosystem and consistent performance have also established it as a reliable language for both web and mobile development, as well as cloud-based services.

        </item>

        <item>
           PHP is a widely used server-side scripting language primarily for web development. Initially, PHP was designed to generate dynamic web pages and is often used with content management systems like WordPress. Its ease of integration with HTML and databases like MySQL has made PHP a popular choice for building web applications. Over the years, PHP has evolved to include advanced features such as object-oriented programming and frameworks like Laravel, which offer tools for faster and more secure web application development. PHP flexibility and wide adoption continue to make it a significant language in the web development world.

        </item>

        <item>
           Python is a high-level programming language designed with an emphasis on simplicity and code readability. Python is widely used across various domains, including web development, data analysis, machine learning, and system automation. Its clean and straightforward syntax makes it a popular choice for beginners, while its versatility and extensive libraries support complex tasks for advanced developers. Python dynamic typing, vast ecosystem of frameworks and tools, and strong community support have contributed to its growth as one of the most popular programming languages for both small projects and large-scale applications.

        </item>
        <item>
           Scala is a programming language that runs on the JVM and combines features from both functional and object-oriented paradigms. It is widely used in the development of large-scale applications that require high scalability, such as distributed systems and big data platforms. Scala support for functional programming allows for concise and expressive code, while its object-oriented capabilities ensure compatibility with Java, making it a versatile choice for developers. Scala is particularly popular in data-intensive environments, often used with frameworks like Apache Spark for big data processing, thanks to its ability to handle concurrent and parallel processing efficiently.

        </item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <integer-array name="data_photo">
        <item>@drawable/c</item>
        <item>@drawable/haskell</item>
        <item>@drawable/javascript</item>
        <item>@drawable/kotlin</item>
        <item>@drawable/cs</item>
        <item>@drawable/golang</item>
        <item>@drawable/java</item>
        <item>@drawable/php</item>
        <item>@drawable/python</item>
        <item>@drawable/scala</item>
    </integer-array>

</resources>